<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shoe in the Door</title>
    <description>Helping organizations tell their story and expand their reach.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:16:40 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:16:40 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roasted Vegetables</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn’t grow up liking brussel sprouts. I don’t know many people that did. In fact we didn’t even really have them at my house, because my parents didn’t like them. Multi-generational brussel sprout trauma is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one magical Thanksgiving I had roasted brussel sprouts. But not just brussel sprouts, beets, carrots, onion, and garlic as well. All roasted in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then roasted root vegetables has been my go-to potluck veggie dish. It’s simple - I only season with olive oil, salt, and pepper. It’s easy to be seasonal - root vegetables have a long season. And it’s actually pretty darn good for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that first time I’ve upped my game by adding parsnips, which are especially lovely when roasted. I’ve also started throwing the left overs into a food processor and making a spread. If you go that way, throw in some fresh garlic or rosemary as the sweetness of the roasted veggies can take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You set your oven to 400 degrees and peel and chop the beets. Toss in a bit of oil and salt, then when the oven gets up to temp roast just the beets on their own for about 20-30 minutes. Otherwise everything  you have will be beet colored and the beets will be underdone. During that first 30 chop everything else up. I don’t peel the carrots or parsnip and if the sprouts are big I chop them in half. Big chop on the onions as well and the garlic I throw in whole. Toss everything with a bit of olive oil, salt and pepper and pop in with the beets for another 30-40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid if things start to look crispy around the edges, that’s how it’s supposed to be. A silicon pad on the sheet pan is ideal, but foil is always a good idea for easy clean up. Leftovers aren’t quite as good, but heat up in the oven, the microwave will kill the texture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/10/roasted-vegetables.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/10/roasted-vegetables.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Event Apart</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very first web conference I attended was the second ever An Event Apart in Atlanta in 2006. Don’t believe me, here I am &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/joetan/123020785/in/pool-aeaatlanta2006/&quot;&gt;eating a hamburger&lt;/a&gt;. I still have that grey undershirt by the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember that trip and that day well. I specifically remember Zeldman’s advice to never respond to an RFP longer than two pages. I can’t recall any other specific insights gained, but I remember walking away feeling like I had tons of work to do to be a real web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well in the 11 years since, I think I’ve done alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the line-up for Seattle 2017, every single session will help me improve. Here are some sessions I’m particularly exctied about and what I’m hoping to get out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Codependent’s Guide to Design Collaboration - Zeldman leads the day off with something where all developers can do better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practical Branding - brand is a big part of what we do at &lt;a href=&quot;http://abravenew.com&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onboarding for Any Situation - we have a few clients that build software and having a framework for a positive first-use experience will be helpful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motion In Design Systems - ahh animation, all the cool kids do it, but how do we make it classy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design Beyond Our Devices - pattern languages are my love language(s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluating Technology - this is my primary area of expertise so I’m interested to learn how others go about this process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New CSS Layout Meets the Real World - grid is almost brand new to me and I can always brush up on flexbox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing with Grid - perhaps the session I’m most exited for, from what I’ve read the grid will save my soul&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design for Real Life - Eric Meyer is respected for a reason, he could talk about rocks and I would go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Joy of Optimizing - I am doing some cool stuff on the code side, optimizing images is another matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 Things You Can and Should Do With SVG - dabbled in SVG, and want to know more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s Build a Website - can’t wait to follow someone’s process start to finish and steal the good stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will will be 11 years to the day since my last An Event Apart. A lot has happened since April 2006, but all that time I’ve proud to be part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluebeanieday.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;blue beanie&lt;/a&gt; wearing club. I’m looking forward to sharpening my skills even further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/05/an-event-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/05/an-event-apart.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snow Sports</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Christina loves to ski and I love her, so knowing that I am going to fall repeatedly over a weekend is worth it. Nordic skiing isn’t a thing where I’m from. Downhill is relegated to what most Seattle folks would call a bunny slope. But I’ve fond gliding on a pair of skis through a winter postcard wonderland is a uniquely Seattle experience for me. Something I’m excited to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t tried it, it’s less than $100 to get out for a weekend and rent the gear, you should try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/04/snow-sports.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/04/snow-sports.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Detroit Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation about Detroit. I know it’s very hipster to say good things about Detroit, but I had a great time there last summer. Far from a city guide, here were my favorite places in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mercury-buger-bar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mercuryburgerbar.com/&quot;&gt;Mercury Buger Bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So nice we ate here twice.Amazing burgers, great beer selection. And if you are going paleo they will but your meat in a bowl. Outdoor seating in the summer is also quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grand-trunk-pub&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.grandtrunk.pub/&quot;&gt;Grand Trunk Pub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cousin took me here for my very first meal in Detroit. I have returned many times. Absolutely amazing beer selection. I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ratebeer.com/beer/goose-island-bourbon-county-stout/8909/&quot;&gt;Bourbon County Stout&lt;/a&gt; on tap there, amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-whisky-parlor&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whiskyparlor.com/&quot;&gt;The Whisky Parlor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proud to say we were there for opening night. I had my first Japanese scotch. Unfortunately it was after a few other ones so I don’t recall the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bucharest-grill&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bucharestgrill.com/&quot;&gt;Bucharest Grill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap big shawarma in a no nonsense bar. If you want a bunch of perfectly grilled meat and a Detroit Brewing lager this is your place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shinola&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shinola.com/&quot;&gt;Shinola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my watch there. I think it’s important for a man to have a watch that will be passed down to his kids. It’s not Swiss or gold, but it is special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;city-market-detroit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/citymarketdetroit/&quot;&gt;City Market Detroit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the Facebook link, but their website is down. This place was a lifesaver, a great grocery store in walking distance of downtown. I spent most of my time in the beer isle where I was able to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greatlakesbrewing.com/christmas-ale&quot;&gt;Great Lakes Christmas&lt;/a&gt; in January, which is just unheard of. I also picked up a bottle of &lt;a href=&quot;http://twojames.com/our-spirits/&quot;&gt;Two James, Grass Widow Bourbon&lt;/a&gt;. It’s still mostly corn, but higher than usually rye make this a winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So apparently all I did in Detroit was eat and drink whiskey. Rest assured it was outside of the hours of the event I was there for. If you know what I mean, you know what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/03/detroit-guide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/03/detroit-guide.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get to Know Your Neighbor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This fall my church, Phinney Ridge Lutheran Church, has hosted a series of classes on Islam. It has been exciting to learn know how uninformed I was about Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the most recent session the Ph.D. that is teaching used a Muslim children’s book’s to share a story from the Quran. That is perhaps the best way to show where we are all at in our understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of fear about Islam or better said about a particular group of people who claim Islam as their reason for the unreasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my visit to Friday prayers at a local mosque I met those whom many fear. An imam whose dressed the same as the Ayatollah or Osama Bin Laden. Though I’m sure that to someone from Arabia the differences in their dress would be obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Imam gave a moving sermon in Arabic. The same language used by ISIS propaganda. Though someone who spoke Arabic would be able to clearly tell them apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These people stopped being “these people” and started being father’s and husband’s and sons. Amazingly humble and hospitable people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we asked what we might do, they said tell people about us. So, in my small way I am. The people of the Idris Mosque in North Seattle are your neighbors. You should get to know them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/30/get-to-know-your-neighbor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/30/get-to-know-your-neighbor.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Garbage Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a dog in your life means picking up shit, there are no two ways around that. It’s the great equalizer of pet ownership. What isn’t equal is the distance you carry it on any given day. And for me, the dawn of garbage day means the least amount of time I shuttle crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every other day a private trash can is off limits. Even if it’s on the curb, even if there are other feces filled bags in there, that’s your trash and I will not trespass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communal dumpsters are another mater. When they are far away from the apartment building and not near overflowing, I feel like they are fair game. Public trash cans in parks are also clearly ok. The small trash cans next to Seattle bus stops are a murky area. In the winter I’m ok using them, but in the summer or if they are near full, I shy away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on garbage day, with your can on the curb, I feel like it’s fine to deposit my bag. But only &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the garbage truck has come by. There are few worse feelings than hauling a can back into your house only to find a lonely, soggy bag of shit at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why it’s soggy, but it always is. It’s probably better that I do not know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you see me dropping a bag of shit into your garbage can or dumpster, know that I have thought long and hard about the moral implications of my actions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/12/29/garbage-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/12/29/garbage-day.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Brought to you by Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been interested in trying out &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and the fact that my hosting service needed renewal game me a good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part was adding the necessary Ruby Gems. I went the not-cool-but-oh-so-easy route of a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; install and all was well. With the exception of having to run the importer as root, which meant that all the posts were owned by root. A simple chown solved that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a lot more development lately, stuff that doesn’t make sense on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://abravenew.com/blog&quot;&gt;A Brave New Blog&lt;/a&gt; maybe I’ll write some more about that here, no promises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/30/now-brought-to-you-by-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/30/now-brought-to-you-by-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fracking Truthers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/6/8558485/fracking-water-contamination-pennsylvania-study&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found a small, regulatory permissible amount of toxic chemicals in drinking water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It even goes on to say, that current regulation would have likely prevented this small contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you would expect drilling groups to say: “We told it was safe, this proves it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no, they basically deny the whole thing and try to make it seem like the study is a fraud. Why? Because only total acceptance of the fracking’s salvific nature is allowed. Any doubters are charlatans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good study that clearly laid out the dangers of improper procedures and that the whole argument that the chemicals don’t make it into drinking water is bunk. It’s an important study to understand if safe fracking is possible, but instead of celebrating the industry dismisses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this disregard for even &lt;strong&gt;supportive&lt;/strong&gt; but cautious science that makes me continue to seriously doubt the industries good faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/05/06/fracking-20truthers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/05/06/fracking-20truthers.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Brave New</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of you know that I left Masterworks in September. What most of you don’t know is that I’ve been working on a partnership with two longtime colleagues and friends, it’s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://abravenew.com&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how excited and pleased I am to be starting this new company/adventure. It’s the culmination of a lot of work and inspiration. The support of my family, the example of entrepreneurs, the encouragement of teachers and mentors and the fellowship of friends all played a part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’d like to ask you to do one more thing for me: spread the word. A Brave New is ready to help nonprofits and small business tell their story and expand their reach. If that sounds like something someone you know could use, drop an email or a tweet or a phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://abravenew.com&quot;&gt;the new website&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/abravenew&quot;&gt;follow us on twitter&lt;/a&gt; and keep in touch. We are going to have some fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/06/a-brave-new.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/02/06/a-brave-new.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great Security Washington State Ferries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I don’t take the ferry nearly as much as I used to, I just got around to turning off email alerts for ferry delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, I needed a password I had long forgot so I sent for a password reset. Here’s the email I received:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/15t.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see the password is redacted, because it was my actual password. I recognized it because I often use a password across a number of accounts that I don’t care about. Password reuse is a security no-no, but it’s quite common and when we are talking about my Washington State Ferry account which holds no personal info beyond an outdated address, I’m not terribly concerned about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is when the password is properly secured. The fact that they could send me my actual password means they are either storing it in plain text or a reversible encryption algorithm. Either way it’s at significantly more risk than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passwords should always be stored using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://crackstation.net/hashing-security.htm&quot;&gt;salted one way encryption scheme&lt;/a&gt;. That way if your database is ever compromised (from inside or outside) only the most common passwords will be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is truly lazy programming to be able to spit back a users password and then to send it via email is downright irresponsible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/01/21/great-security-wsf.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/01/21/great-security-wsf.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
