<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shoe in the Door</title>
    <description>Helping organizations tell their story and expand their reach.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 21:31:58 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 21:31:58 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Pennsylvania</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, Vote. Especially if you live in Pennsylvania. If you are registered in Pennsylvania, you should vote in person. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.votespa.com/Voting-in-PA/Pages/Voting-at-a-Polling-Place.aspx&quot;&gt;find a polling place here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help getting to the your polling place, call someone. If you are registered with a political party, call your county office. They want you to vote and will help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pennsylvanians may decide this election and every vote cast in Pennsylvania matters and should be counted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I think you should vote for Joe Biden for President. I did. Ths is the first time I’ve supported a Democrat for President. I worked for &lt;a href=&quot;https://justfacts.votesmart.org/candidate/evaluations/27054/rick-santorum&quot;&gt;Senator Rick Santorum&lt;/a&gt;. I interned at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heritage.org/about-heritage/mission&quot;&gt;Heritage Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commonwealthfoundation.org/about/&quot;&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. I went to Grove &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gcc.edu/Home/Our-Story/Faith-Freedom&quot;&gt;City College&lt;/a&gt;. I am not a socialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 25, 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trumps-ukraine-call-transcript-read-the-document&quot;&gt;President Trump had a phone call with the President of Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s a lot of talk about Biden’s son, that Biden stopped the prosecution and a lot of people want to find out about that. So whatever you can do with the Attorney General would be great. Biden went around bragging that he stopped the prosecution so if you can look into it…It sounds horrible to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The President of the United States asked a foreign leader to investigate his most likely (and eventual) opponent. This is not acceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if your kid, or niece, told you they asked some kids from the next town over to dig up dirt on the person they were running against for Class President. Would you be excited about that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect more from the President of the United States. I think you should as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/01/vote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/11/01/vote.html</guid>
        
        <category>vote</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-7</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wolf was the chief. The beast who made short work of two villagers before our eyes was the very man sworn to protect this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have we walked into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wanted us to protect this village, all the while he was hunting it? He needed us to stand up to a few dozen men, when he could turn into a fire breathing, ten foot tall, wolf?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something is not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our trade at the chapel in Vestygg was merchants barely getting through the door, tossing their coins into the basked my father had invented, and moving on. Our coffer basked took the time to ask the Lady’s favor from minutes to seconds, and the donations poured in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t all a volume business. There were the confessors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inaction is the only sin in the worship of the Lady. Moral codes of absolute right and wrong rarely work in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, one of Pelor’s sunnies can do ethical summersaults to prove that a woman is justified to steal bread to feed her starving children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ask the same summer priests what that same woman should do if she can only steal one loaf, but has two children and they freeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can a god tell someone there is a right choice in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tell her to break the loaf in half, and ask Tymora to be kind. Luck and chance sustain when goodness and mercy can not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The penitent would come to our chapel and confess their indecision. The Abbott would listen, and nod, and tell them what to do. Sometimes it was his best judgement, sometimes it was what they wanted to hear so he could go back to the tavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when someone was droning on for particularity long, and wasn’t keping the coppers dropping in the coffer, the Abbot would excuse himself come to my cell, and ask me to take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is why the first bit of wisdom he taught me was how to have the Lady transform me into someone else. It’s also why he taught me how to mimic voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would ask the Lady to make me look like the Abbott, check the mirror and walk back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from a burden, these encounters were my only contact with the outside world. I would revel in the details. My aim was to ask the question that unlocked their indecision – like a key turning a bolt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how I knew something was wrong in this village. Why would only one specific hut, not on the edge of the village be attacked? Why one boy, but not another, why now? Who in the village could leave unseen when everyone shares their tent with others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked Shaba about that, she barely understood why. The chief is the only one that could come and go as he pleased, and apparently his pleasure was to hunt his kith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/28/d-and-d-volume-1-7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/09/28/d-and-d-volume-1-7.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-6</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize I have never been cold. When you grow up sharing a monk’s cell, even a small oil lamp will keep you warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fall, my father and I hunted for the deer that would keep us fed through the winter. Leaving before first light I could often see my breath, but I wasn’t cold. I was free. We would stay in the woods all day, butchering anything we would take, and wrapping it in paper so we could smuggle it back in after dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were long days, but not cold days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know cold now. As we trudge towards the village, the the stinging salt spray quickly coats my robes. If this place doesn’t give us shelter, we won’t make it through the day, let alone the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard of these islands of the far north, isolated, just the way the elves like it. Fortunately Kirrix and Elros speak elvish and secure us freedom to enter the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bargain for cloaks, but the reality is I would have given the coin from my forehead for the warmth these cloaks provide. Lady forgive me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly the next hour is a blur, we trudge up to see the leader of this village, tell him our lie, tell him the truth, and he doesn’t slit our throats. That is enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as I lay down in their infirmary I feel some measure of warmth. As I see the others fall off to sleep, I pull out the lockbox we found in the temple. I want desperately to hear that tune again, but I have on idea if opening the box here wil make the entire structure collapse around us. And I’m too tired to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I awaken to the chief telling us that few will stay and fight, and that blurry hour comes back to me. We’ve agreed to help this village fend off Lady Sky’s enforcers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m wanted in Ostia and Rudainia, why not add Kaldygg to the list! I have no more home, and Lady Sky is a tyrant. Let’s see what luck the true Lady can bring this village at the icy end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/d-and-d-volume-1-6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/09/21/d-and-d-volume-1-6.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-5</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We survived him. Another Black Knight has fallen and now we have the phylactery, whatever that is. I’m not even sure if the Knight thing was alive before it stopped moving, but we once again have ended something’s existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t my path. I have been bouncing from inn to inn, battle, to negotiation, to battle, but for what? I don’t seek fortune or fame. I have no grudge with these people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I do have now is an object of immense power and value. And I know that the object is desired by someone in the court at Rausten&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning and plotting as Kirrix and I walk back in the library to be greeted by 20 crossbowman, a priest, and some Rudainian high nobel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like the law has caught up to us. We dash back into the sanctuary of the Library and fling the door shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the key I picked up in the library seems to lock the doors with some arcane magic so we have tome to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have no ideas, there is no way out of this room, and while we may be able to bottle them up in the door, eventually we will be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do have the lockbox. We have no idea what’s in it, but we know that the combination was found in a book about demonic planar binding. That doesn’t bode well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set the lockbox in front of the threshold and wait for the door to fling open. After his dip in the black starry ooze, Kirrix, has some new abilities and dials the combination from across the room as the door flings open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead of a demon appearing a simple tune plays. I lower my bow. I know this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a memory that is familiar and foreign all at the same time. Like something that was willed into my memory. But the memory is so caring. I feel so safe, so loved. More loved than I have since I was thrust out of the chapel back in Vestygg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tune ends too soon a deep rumble begins and the floor shifts under my feet. The black ooze is bubbling and expanding. Without a word, we all know it’s time to leave. I follow my companions out the door and see chaos on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the time to pick up the box and take a look back at where the statue of Sariel Silvertree once stood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pompous priest of Pelor is encouraging his brethren to continue the fight. I hop on the table with him and humbly suggest that neither Pelor nor the Lady will be getting anyone out of this mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I run down the table and get to the door, I see Walter stumbling. We left him behind. My stomach sinks as the Lady gives my voice strength to tell Walter to jump on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He does and the damned priest tries to stop him. These Divine Brotherhood bastards don’t know when to quit. As Walter tries to free himself from the priest grasp they both tumble into the abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Library continues to collapse around us I don’t have time to think more about our lost friend. We clamber back up into the tall tower and everything feels more stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose to go through the door that we think takes us to the North. We step into the snow, wrap our cloaks around us and begin to trudge to some smoke we see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are on the run. Most who know of us are dead, but not all. We have an object powerful enough to take life with a touch. Desired by other worldly Knights and members of the royal court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen merchants toss dozens of coins into my offering plate asking for the Lady to bring them fortune. But not even toss a copper to the beggars on their way out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lady doesn’t make the rich. Anymore than Beshaba makes the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck is sewn throughout the World without much care. What we do with that fortune is the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have some fortune. The Lady favors the bold. Maybe we can turn the world on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume 1-4 was skipped because it was just combat. Not the most fun to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/31/d-and-d-volume-1-5.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/08/31/d-and-d-volume-1-5.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-3</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pelor&quot;&gt;Pelor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brigand did well to replace Alhandra’s holy medallion. I’m surprised he did knowing his penchant for trinkets. That boy priest looks to have talked sense in to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where have I seen this Lady worshiper before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said you wanted the box, not what was in it.” He said as he handed it over. What a clever boy. I usually don’t allow such acts of insolence to my faithful, but this band of the Divine Brotherhood throw my name around like a cheap parlor trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few hours earlier those idiots fleeced some bigger idiot Rudainians. The reversal pleased me. This boy priest has won my blessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not often my eye lingers on the material plane, but to see Alhandra, my faithful servant, picked apart by that abomination of an abomination. Such a forsaken place devoid of any true light, mired in darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did these survive when my champion had fallen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello there!” the brigand greets a dead elf. It’s amazing to me these fools got the door open but they did. I can’t imagine how their puny brains can comprehend the portals they uncovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I open my mind and can be anywhere. I can see each of them born, dead, reborn. I can jump to any point in their story, or any place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for them to be able to step through a doorway and be thousands of miles away. Oh it’s such a joy to see their smug faces smacked with a bit of the impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They made short work of the Owlbear that fell Alhandra. Although they could have avoided it entirely if the Weaver hadn’t been going on about his eyes, or lack thereof. Seemed an odd moment for story time, but I don’t pretend to understand humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Them seem to have no fear of the dark abomination that floods the sanctuary. I can’t even gaze at it without feeling sick. It’s the complete absence of light, everything I stand for, everting I am for this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way my light brings justice to everything it touches, this darkness brings corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The darwf reduced to a skelton surrounded by a gelatinous mass of pure nothingness. They fought that with such abandon. How lucky they are they do not know the evil that fuels these foul beasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brigand has done well. There will come a time when he will call on me and I will answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lady may bring luck, but I bring the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/09/d-and-d-volume-1-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/08/09/d-and-d-volume-1-3.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;walter&quot;&gt;Walter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done what I can for them, and they hardly take notice. The uneven rocking of the boat tells me that we have yet to cross the river, but what’s troubling is not what I feel under my bones, but what I can’t smell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reek as we’ve left Flod hasn’t given way to salt air or decaying reed grasses. It’s as if we are sailing off the edge of the map. I can hear water lapping on the shore, but no scent of wood in water or drying fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat bumps to a halt, and I’m clumsily helped out on to the shore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally a smell, though not a pleasant one. Poorly butchered meat and salt. This place is not in ballance, not connected. Silent. It’s not just Rudainia that has gone silent but the great five pointed web itself has cessed to vibrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some meaningless banter and an exchange of some bobble for information gave my adventuring companions enough courage to cross the river. But no one asks me what I think, and I’m so far from home I don’t have much choice but to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trudge through a root infested path and then out onto unkempt cobble stones when I can feel a breeze and with it the first hint of life. Forest, alive, but not living. Ripe with decay and malice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently we come to a gap in a bridge and I’m unceremoniously lowered onto two ropes and told to shuffle across by my armpits. I slip half way through and while they debate about how they might help me up, I right myself. I’m blind, not helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel the space close in and the smell of the forest deepens, we slow and I hear a new voice hoarsely calling, I can’t make it out, sounds like names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cocky one, Bryce, whispers in my ear, “What do you smell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smug little bastard. He thinks he’s smarter than everyone, but he knows nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tell him, “the forest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He brings me closer to the new voice, and as I lean in, I feel a spongy hand on my chest and suddenly I’m thrust 10 feet backward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there the usual sounds of slashing and stabbing. These men and half-elves have little imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A arrow whistles and the forest comes alive. I lack the vocabulary to describe the language of the trees, but I can smell their now angry breath on the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear a the crack of a whip, and then another and Bryce cries out. A smash of glass and then heat and the sound of cracking, smoking wet wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve made our way to the door of this place, but it has announced we are not welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/04/d-and-d-vol-1-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/08/04/d-and-d-vol-1-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-1</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are shaken from having encountered, them. I have never seen anything, like them. Black ooze pouring from where Kirrix’s rapier found it’s purchase. Now safe inside the thick walls of the Keep of Flod, we pause a moment in the great hall, deciding what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still disguised as Sven, the Lady blessing me with this illusion. We have to choose about going down, most likely to the boathouse and escape, or going up to, further explore the keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lead the way up, to the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upper level of the keep is deserted, probably because we just dispatched it’s previous resident. What have I gotten myself into. I have no trouble defending myself, but we just murdered that inquisitor for no other reason than the Hand told us to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have time for moralizing later. We push into a room the reeks of the same stench that came from them. A pool of black ooze sits on the floor, not contained, but not spreading out. It bubbles as Friq approaches and I see him shake his gloved hand like he’s been stung by a bee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kirrix moves to the winch holding a chain that ends in the pool of the ooze and slowly starts to raise the chain. Friq raises his crossbow and I string my longbow. A bald head emerges and then a scarred face. The tar like blackness drips off like blood and then, my ears are ringing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m covered with dust and the wind and rain is lashing against me. A dark figure towers in a gaping hole where the wall had just been. The five stories between us and the earth did not stop his approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the impetuous Kirrix is stunned and slams the release to lower the body back into the tar. We back away slowly knowing that we know not what this is. As the Black Knight pulls the body out of the ooze we hear him say “Brother!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now time to go. We move quickly through the great hall and down to the boat launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kirrix and Friq are searching for, who knows what, and I just want to get out of there. The gash on my shoulder where one of them caught me is staring to throb with pain, so I stick my head in the storeroom and suggest it’s time to get the flock out of here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’ve overstayed our welcome. More decaying villagers shuffle towards us. Elros gets Walter to the boat, and I move to prevent any of them from getting to the gangway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kirrix and Friq and still in the storeroom and suddenly I’m surrounded by three of them. I called on Tymora earlier to banish these devils and she did not answer. I ask her to rain down sacred fire and manage to slow one down, but not before another knocks me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I remember, is the smell of blood on Friq’s copper armor. I know it’s mine, because they don’t bleed. Friq slouches me off his shoulder, and I crumple in the stern of the boat as we row out into the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pray we are headed back to the village where I can rest and be healed, but I feel like we ar heading away from shore, closer to the cursed shores of Grado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indominable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/d-and-d-vol-1-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/07/27/d-and-d-vol-1-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Webconnex is Awesome</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Five minutes after I knew I was going to be leaving A Brave New, I sent &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nanno77&quot;&gt;Nanno&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webconnex.com/&quot;&gt;Webconnex&lt;/a&gt; a message, asking if they had any openings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank goodness they never removed me from Slack!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the week I had an offer. Webconnex, in many ways, saved our family in a really tough spot. And they never stopped showing up. I can’t say enough about how amazing everyone is. It is the best culture of any place I’ve worked. And I don’t expect any place to live up to its legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited to be moving on to &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/23/WP-VIP.html&quot;&gt;WordPress VIP&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to take some time to plug Webconnex’s awesome products. The people are great, but the software is just ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know we are in Pandemic times, but if you run events you can’t find a more cost-effective, flexible, customizable solution. If you are using EventBrite you could be saving $10,000 a year or more with Webconnnex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, Jacob, I need virtual events. No problem. The current virtual event system will get you started, but take it from me, in the next month they are going to blow that way with a brand new offering. Think zoom, but in the browser. No zoom bombing, full control, moderation and chat. And that’s just the beginning. This was my last project and it’s something the team can be super proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And behind all this amazing software it the best support team — ever. They are so good Webconnex doesn’t even call them support, they call them solutions. Having trouble on a Saturday? Brandon will call you and walk you through updating your app. Feeling stressed from your event? Maci will put together a care package that will take your mind off everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, their satisfaction ratings are off the charts. If you have a problem with the software I guarantee that the human on the other end of the chat will make it their problem until it’s fixed or you have a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t even talk about online giving for nonprofits, or reserved seating, or time-slot ticketing. Or the ability to add your own custom logic to hide/show form fields, adjust pricing, basically whatever you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need ticketing, event registration, or online giving you need to take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webconnex.com/&quot;&gt;Webconnex&lt;/a&gt;. If you aren’t dialing &lt;a href=&quot;tel:+18889583729&quot;&gt;(888) 958-3729&lt;/a&gt; right now, then &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jake@shoeinthedoor.com&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I’ll convince you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t say it enough when I worked there, because some part of me felt like it was wrong to promote my own company. But you heard it here folks, Webconnex is the best. PERIOD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/23/Webconnex.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/06/23/Webconnex.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to WordPress VIP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited announce that next week I’m starting at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wpvip.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress VIP&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been a WordPress and Automattic fan since the early 2000’s. I’ve built dozen of sites using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress.org&lt;/a&gt; over the years and spoken at two WordCamps Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s all kinds of reason I’m making this change, but one of them is the amazing WordPress community. I wanted to take this moment to thank some members of that community that have helped me along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First is the person who introduced me to WordPress: Joe Tan. Ironically, and inexplicable, Joe does not have a website. Whenever I have a technical problem I can’t solve, WordPress or otherwise. Joe is my first call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t talk about Joe without talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbox9.com&quot;&gt;Michael Schafer&lt;/a&gt;. Michael was Joe and my boss and Creative Directory at Silas Partners. No website there either because our wonderful start-up got acquired by a company to which I simply will not link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can wholeheartedly endorse Michael’s design studio &lt;a href=&quot;https://openbox9.com&quot;&gt;openbox9&lt;/a&gt;. If you are a non-profit, and if no one else can help, and if you can find them (not hard just click the link), these lovely people really are the A-Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly a lot of love goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abravenew.com/&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;. When Josh, Polly, and I started our little digital agency, who would know what it would become. I was able to lead the technical side of some amazing WordPress projects there. If you are a for-profit, look no futher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three last community member mentions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eriktdesign.com/&quot;&gt;Erik Teichman&lt;/a&gt; for introducing me to Metabox.io. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tracyappsdesign.com/&quot;&gt;Tracy Apps&lt;/a&gt; for being the oldest WP G. I know. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://jillbinder.com/&quot;&gt;Jill Binder&lt;/a&gt; who is doing amazing work making sure the community is hearing from everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to be writing more in this space as I dive into Automattic and WordPress VIP. It’s been a hard saying goodbye to Webconnex, but that’s a subject for the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/06/23/Webconnex.html&quot;&gt;next post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/23/WP-VIP.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/06/23/WP-VIP.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WordCamp Seattle 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my second year at WordCamp and I’m excited to learn more about creating content and this thing called Gutenberg? Perhaps you’ve heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I take notes, so any errors are likely mine not the speaker. I’ll be updating this as we go through the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keynote-bridget-willard--community-observe-include-accept&quot;&gt;Keynote: Bridget Willard – Community: Observe, Include, Accept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridget is from Orange County. And is Orange County excited for a Seattle crowd. At 9am. On a Saturday. It’s difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community is not just a noun, it’s a verb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are all just working on a group project like it’s 4th grade – and sometimes we fight like it too&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are wired to be connected to each other, and when we are deprived of that connection it affects us spiritually, emotionally, physically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It’s so illegally cold in Minnesota”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“If you keep talking, I’m going to call on you, because I have a great view.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Did you know that these are all your friends? Sometimes it just helps to hear it.” Life happens to people (tell me about it), we need to hold each other in those times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nouns have no meaning, if the behavior doesn’t go with it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We like to think we make logical decisions, but we make emotional decisions and reverse engineer the logic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We can’t build this thing called WordPress if we all think the same.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our computers are de-humanizing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s really talking about hospitality, which is a core value of Christianity (at least as I practice it). It is fascinating to hear someone basically preach on The Sermon on the Mount, but from a totally secular perspective. Observe, Include, and Accept as core values are values of the WordPress community and of the Christian community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that may come as a surprise, based on how Christianity is practiced in the United States today, but for me, and my community it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andrew-taylor---the-benefits-of-testing-and-automation&quot;&gt;Andrew Taylor - The Benefits of Testing and Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a maintainer of websites. We pick up projects and we have to keep them going over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe there is a better way than shoving everything on a staging site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead if you test continuously, after every change less messes to detangle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checking things you didn’t work on is boring, time consuming, and hard to bill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated testing is the road less traveled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual regression as baseline - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/garris/BackstopJ&quot;&gt;Backstop JS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examining performance - &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse/&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automated testing is important in WordPress, but even more important with the work I’m doing at &lt;a href=&quot;http;//webconnex.com&quot;&gt;WebConnex&lt;/a&gt;. Implementing visual regression testing is on my list to get started on day 1, the performance testing will actually be a bit easier to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jonathan-peck---the-other-wpml-machine-learning--ai-in-wordpress&quot;&gt;Jonathan Peck - The other WPML: Machine Learning / Ai in WordPress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advocate for &lt;a href=&quot;https://algorithmia.com/&quot;&gt;Algorithmia&lt;/a&gt;, which does Machine Learning hosting. What follows are ideas for how we could use this at WebConnex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recommender engine - show the right race length&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI based, dynamic ambassador discount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use tweet sentiment to figure out how people feel about the event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team name/GroupRev suggestion based on past performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suggestion on fields to add/remove based on performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object detection for alt tags of images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text summarization for meta descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated statement images for social media (Cloudinary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talked walked a fine line between pitch and information. I think it ended up fairly pitchy, but the service looks helpful, so I care a bit less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taylor-waldon---making-content-part-of-company-culture&quot;&gt;Taylor Waldon - Making Content Part of Company Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor has been doing content since college working at a food service company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic permission marketing thinking create: relevant, timely, expected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are creating the content out of the final publishing medium, you need to re-edit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Content Matrix&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Value&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Key Message&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Key Message&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog Post Template
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;title&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;author&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;category&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;image direction&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;target audience&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;offer/value&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;keyword&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;hook/meta description&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule, free Google calendar if you need more &lt;a href=&quot;https://coschedule.com/&quot;&gt;CoSchedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was done in 20 minutes. It was actually a significantly dense introduction to content management. As someone immersed in that world for years it was helpful. If I were brand new, I don’t think I would have gotten as much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bob-dunn---how-to-repurpose-a-single-piece-of-content-into-a-lot-of-content&quot;&gt;Bob Dunn - How to Repurpose a Single Piece of Content Into a Lot of Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned a camera on for this session and counted people there were 90 people +/- 5 at this session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internal links give Google a roadmap for your website, basically pillar pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating content is the biggest way he grows his traffic
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tweaks: add content, links to newer posts, but all in context&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turns: revive or bury posts, deleting is the easy way with redirect, harder way is to rethink&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Twists: save as draft, rewrite, and schedule&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up links as post title (no dates in URL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use audio and video (duh), turn audio into videoless video, less duh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot;&gt;Amazon Polly&lt;/a&gt; to transcribe text posts to audio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extractions: Inverviews, tips, lists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One post serves all
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Monday: email list&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tuesday: blog&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wednesday: talking head video&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thursday: podcast&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When re-using content make sure to use canonical URLs for your extractions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He’s tried time and again to make money from his most popular blog post, but he just can’t - he just makes people happy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good reminder to look at content after it’s published and re-link it to more modern content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devin-walker---if-you-build-it-right-they-will-come--creating-truly-valuable-wordpress-products-and-services&quot;&gt;Devin Walker - If You Build It (Right), They Will Come – Creating Truly Valuable WordPress Products and Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devin works for Give WP. He started his talk going through a bunch of different business models from freelancer to large company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking about Why first &lt;a href=&quot;https://startwithwhy.com/&quot;&gt;Start with Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GiveWP’s mission is to democratize generosity, so you don’t have to pay a SaaS provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are both product and service opportunities on top of WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GiveWP started as a services company that was building nonprofit sites and was hacking together a donation solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advocating functional specs, I’m not a fan, I say build the thing ala 37Signals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your idea is a car, don’t start with a wheel, start with a scooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how true the “If you build it they will come” message is for WordPress tools. The overall, measured, systematic approach to starting a business Devin set out does mean success is more likely, but not assured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andrea-zoellner---storytelling-with-gutenberg-how-to-use-the-new-editor-to-boost-your-blog&quot;&gt;Andrea Zoellner - Storytelling with Gutenberg: How to Use the New Editor to Boost Your Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrea is an end user, so she focused on content creation and is excited about Gutenberg as was Taylor, another content creator. It’s probably a good sign for WordPress. There are way more content creators using WordPress than developers. Developers are likely much louder voices, but the creators will win out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Referencing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall/index.html#/?part=tunnel-creek&quot;&gt;Snowfall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nearly 1/3 of visitors to page were new to the NY Times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“With Gutenberg anyone can Snowfall”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gutenberg tips&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add styles to your text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diversify your images - use gallery to display 3- or 4-up feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrate other post types, Adding shortcodes is easier, but still not as easy as if the shortcode became a block&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add multi-media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add breathing room, much better than adding a bunch of empty spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in a call to action, button blocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify your workflow, re-usable blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very clear that for 95 percent of things you don’t need commercial themes anymore. I’ve long been an advocate of lean, performant custom themes, but Gutenberg makes that argument that much more compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robert-nissenbaum---a-hypothesis-on-the-future-impact-of-gutenberg-on-seo&quot;&gt;Robert Nissenbaum - A Hypothesis on the Future Impact of Gutenberg on SEO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s not a developer. So all this hullabaloo doesn’t matter as much to him. His theory as to “Why Gutenberg?” How we consume content is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile is continuing to increase both as a percentage of traffic and time on site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If how content is consumed changes, how we publish has to change as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve done it at the macro level, now we have to think about the micro-content level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The web and WordPress isn’t going to be about pages, it’s about blocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If Yoast (our default SEO tool) thinks about pages, how do we make it think about blocks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if we did SEO on individual blocks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perhaps the media library is a cue as to a future content block library&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe this can be a way to avoid duplicate content, so that Google understands the atomic pieces of content are re-used but the particular composition is unique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting theory, but I’m not sold. Google can’t figure out what a “block” is, unless it’s served as part of a sitemap.xml somehow. It would seem a very large shift from Google to not think about the document as the base unit of the internet. Especially since that’s how individuals consume content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see why Google would want to go this way. If we allow Google to serve individual blocks, out of context, then people are using Google not our sites. It’s like the worst of AMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do agree that thinking this way will get you better content, so it’s sensible on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jocelyn-mozak---clone-yourself-through-automation&quot;&gt;Jocelyn Mozak - Clone Yourself Through Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jocelyn is an agency owner and she talked about how she worked on automation in her own business. Specifically looking at how she uses automation in the sales process and onboarding process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Automation is a mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replies to requests for a website with a questionnaire and a link to schedule a meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At each step she is sending people to her email marketing and tagging people based on actions and sending automated emails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can’t automate the sales call and proposal, but can automate getting the proposal signed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow-ups through while the proposal is about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once signed, automated email and then back to scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using Gravity forms and Zapier to auto create accounts in multiple software platfoms (Slack, accounting, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the project, tag the client to automatically ask for testimonials or sell maintenance plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jacob-smith---from-developer-to-entrepreneur&quot;&gt;Jacob Smith - From Developer to Entrepreneur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh wait that’s me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shoeinthedoor.com/files/WordCamp-Seattle-2018-JacobWSmith-Presentation.pdf&quot;&gt;Here are the slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/10/wordcamp-seattle-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/10/wordcamp-seattle-2018.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
