<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shoe in the Door</title>
    <description>Helping organizations tell their story and expand their reach.</description>
    <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://shoeinthedoor.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 13:19:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 13:19:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-11</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;thenardier&quot;&gt;Thenardier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no tracker, but you don’t have to be to follow the rut marks of that cart. I was about 1/4 mile behind them when all of a sudden the ruts stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They didn’t turn off, the just stopped, as did all the footprints in the snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ranger is indeed among them I thought as I sped my rescently stolen horse to a trot. No need to go slow now, either I’ll never find them or I’ll run right into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two miles down the road I could have sworn that I heard the creak of a cart wheel, but it could have been the wind. This was not my terrain and the sooner I got back into a town the safer I would feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m on the road, I’m dressed as a nobleman. Better to be prey and lure in the predator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recalled the day when I first met Bryce. Only he didn’t call himself that at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get wind of petty coups in my line of work. Always a good time to make a few coins. It’s also the ony thing that would drag me as far North as Vestygg. I was on my way out of town as the old Lord was being lead to the stockade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then ahead of me, in the trees, a portal opened and something came tumbling out. With just a satchel the boy priest landed in a heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m luring in highwaymen, traveling alone is my usual mode, but traveling with a priest has its advantages. He kept to the trees, but stealthy he was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped my horse and yelled out, “No need to hide priest. In fact, I could use some prayers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of a priest, a sea captain peered around the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No priest here.” brogued from the captain’s lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a casual hearer, this mimicry would pass muster, but I know what I’m seeing and I know how the Lady’s servants work. You study one side of a coin long enough, you are bound to pick up something about the obverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh well then ahoy captain, won’t you walk with me?” I questioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear can’t be disguised. This boy was out of his depth. He sauntered, or attempted to saunter down the slope and seemed happy to have the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode and talked, he told me of his ship: The Seaboard. It had a mast, and sails, and beyond that not much detail. And of Vestygg he couldn’t describe much more than what you can see from the chapel near the Market gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the time past he hardly noticed that he no longer looked like the sea captain, but still was affecting the accent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You see the sea, she is, a cruel mistress, she is.” he opined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As cruel as Tymora?” I barbed. And he took the bait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Lady is not cruel,” he said as he pointed a finger at me. A finger attached to an arm no longer adorned with the fine robe of the sea captain, but of the simple cloak of a priest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never heard his whole story, but he did admit to being a novice from Vestygg, it was about then we were robbed, right on schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking like easy pickings is actually fairly easy. These were the type that ride along with you for a while to size you up and get you when you aren’t looking. This time it was at dinner that I found myself with a knife to my throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had let it happen, and I was ready to break free when I was blinded by golden flames that burned the hat right off my attacker. He fled into the night, tunic smoldering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Bryce had no idea what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I, I, just asked the Lady to protect you,” he stammered, “I never meant to hurt anyone!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Lady works in mysterious ways.” I lied. It is true that gods are fickle but my experience is Tymora tends to protect with deception not with fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My young friend must be holding some hurt, some anger. Something that makes his prayers have urgency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures. I’m starting to write a parallel story focused on Thenardier, a Rouge Mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/03/08/d-and-d-volume-1-11.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/03/08/d-and-d-volume-1-11.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-10</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;thenardier&quot;&gt;Thenardier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to Martin’s place the windows were darkened. I was in a hurry to get out of town as I had already sold my spells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love working the South. No one wonders why I’m walking around with uncut diamonds worth a few thousand gold in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at Martin’s to pay him his cut. If you are going to work a game, always better to have the owner on your side. Martin prefers to take this shady business around back. As I walked around to the alley, a bleeding, burnt, Hunter stormed through Martin’s back door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, so it appears as if someone got to the bounty hunters first. This fellow looked pissed, so I just hung around outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you know they had a caster!,” the half-orc bellowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keep it down Oban, you’ll wake the misses,” hissed Martin in reply. “No, of course not, a caster?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They are all dead, three half-orcs. I saw Zargoz cut down by a beam of light, there was no blood, no blood, no blood.” Oban repeated as his voice trailed off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin was smart enough not to say anything. An angry half-orc is not one to be trifled with. I thought I heard something like a cry but more like a moan and then Martin came flying into the alley landing in a heap next in the gutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oban notched an arrow and held it to the back of Matin’s head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ll pay for their deaths in blood dwarf!” the mercenary snarled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, normally I would consider this a fortuitous event. With Martin dead, I could keep his cut. And there would be one less person alive who knew me. Well not really me. Martin thought I was a courier for a big wig in Halesport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth was I was the bigwig too. I had been writing to Martin as Freidiah, the owner of The Bearded Lady, a brothel and gambling house in Halesport. I told him I knew a card shark that was looking for a game to take, and if he was willing to get this shark into the game, he would get a cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am never myself. With each encounter I invent a new identity. No one sees me twice. In fact the fence that bought the spells thinks I’m Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, like I said, Martin dead was mostly upside to me, but the fact that the half-orc was here meant the $50,000 gold reward was still up for grabs. And the fact that this Hunter couldn’t tell the difference between a caster and a cleric meant that I knew more than Martin or Oban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s not a caster, he follows the Lady.” I offered, slinking from the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I expected the bow was turned on me, but my disguise added a few inches of padding and I had a few tricks up my sleave so I wasn’t worried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, by all means keep that bow pointed at Martin, my master would let me pocket his cut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My gambit was right. The bounty hunter was worried about his friends, but more worried about his money. With that, the half-orc lowered his bow, Martin got to his feet and ushered us back inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oban, still spitting with rage and grief said, “Talk fast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can’t say I’m one for fast talk, fast women maybe, but not fast talk.” I drawled. “But it’s easy to mistake a cleric for a caster. It looks the same, but the power comes from a different place.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well this one moved himself from inside to outside in a second. And when I ran through him, he shattered into pieces.” Oban grumbled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Certainly a worshiper of the Lady then.” I replied, “She grants all sorts of favors to those that follow her.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So they still live?” I continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aye, I left them right where we followed them to. I can’t go back in there alone, it’s not worth $50,000 gold pieces.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t forget about my cut,” Martin jumped back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both I and the half-orc turned our gaze to him, and he shrank from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said to Martin, “Our mutual friend told me about the cleric.” “He also told me that those halflings blew your bar to bits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this Oban chuckled. “Indeed they did. We were waiting outside like you asked when the Prince stepped out of the door, just for a second before he got blown back inside. The blast nearly ripped the whole side of the building.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there was any color left in Martin’s face it drained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s what you get for letting halflings trade various and sundry in your bar.” I quiped. Turning to Oban I said, “Where did you leave them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I counted out the few gold I owed Martin as Oban described the storehouse where they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can’t imagine they are still there, and if they are, I doubt you could take them,” Oban said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I ride for Halesport tonight, but if you keep an eye on them and send a raven to the Bearded Lady in Halesport, Freidiah will send you the firepower you need.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slipped into the night and left them to haggle. I might still get lucky and Martin might get killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to walk towards the storehouse. I was going to head out of town, but now I had something far more interesting to tend too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I too follow a Lady. I’m not a cleric, too much groveling. But I do bring misfortune, and I was looking forward to visiting misfortune on these adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures. I’m starting to write a parallel story focused on Thenardier, a Rouge Mastermind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/03/02/d-and-d-volume-1-10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/03/02/d-and-d-volume-1-10.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-9</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;thenardier&quot;&gt;Thenardier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I was in trouble when four people walked through the fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been casing this game for weeks. High stakes, spells as currency, and very exclusive. You had to be a dwarf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took quite a bit of persuasion to get the potion I had been using. For the past week, I had choked down the smell stuff, walked into a dwarf bar and lost money. I only had two vile vials left when I got the invite to the game at the Hound’s Tooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally it was my night. I got to the Hound’s Tooth early. Early enough to see the three little-folk arrive conspicuously separately. It takes a con to know a con. These three were working together, but seemed small time, unlikely to disrupt my play. If anything a little ruckus at the right time would help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then a knight and three half-elves come strolling into the bar. Not through the front door mind you, but from the fireplace. And not just any knight. A knight with a 50,000 gold piece price on his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a different game to play tonight, but once I cleaned these dwarfs out, I could probably make some quick money on my way out of town. Any bounty hunter in 100 miles would pay handsomely for the whereabouts of these four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheating is easy when you are actually a foot taller than you appear to be. My marks have no idea I can see their cards quite clearly from up in the rafters. That’s all the advantage I need to start cleaning up. I just need a bit longer when I feel the potion wearing off. I need a distraction, and if on queue a table flips over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect, just the ruckus I need to quickly down another slug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then it gets to be just a bit too much rukus. The dwarf swings his wand towards the halfling circling behind the table we all duck, but I can’t get under the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jarl Shueniff tries to shove my head down, but instead he pushes my back and my chest bounces of the edge of the table and he knows something is up. I draw my dagger to make sure he never figures it out when suddenly I’m not worried about it anymore, and it appears neither is he.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A halfling has an arrow through his hand and the knight is screaming at some girl, but I’m quite calm and ready to get back to the game. The darkly dressed half-elf starts a tune. A halfling is run through behind me and I get my feet out of the way. Despite all this I am feeling calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the priest throws some holy water in the air and suddenly I remember that I may have to kill Shueniff. That thought is quickly forgotten when a massive human hurtles towards us. This human missile turns the third member of the halfling tro into pink mist before throwing the table into the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shueniff seems to have bigger worries than me and he and the others leave the smoldering remains of the tavern. The four travelers pay no mind to me as I pick up the discarded spells. An even bigger night than I had planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t overstay my welcome and leave just in time to hear a darkly cloaked, drunk dwarf talk of a safe house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think these four have an idea what they have gotten themselves into. They would be better off walking back through that fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/02/24/d-and-d-volume-1-9.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2021/02/24/d-and-d-volume-1-9.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-8</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve helped kill an Inquisitor. Twice. I’ve helped kill Rudainia Soldiers. I’ve helped kill street urchins. I’ve fought on the side of slavers against those who would set slaves free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But along the way I have stopped a servant of Beshaba and experienced the glory of the Lady in my presence. She has honored us with her words and encouraged us on our quest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a bastard’s bastard from a forgotten corner of Norgaard. I am the Lady’s chosen servant. I’m barely a man in human terms and hardly a boy in elf terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am between two worlds, two continents and aligned with powers I can’t possibly understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How am I not paralyzed by fear and doubt? It is only in my zealous belief that this quest is from Tymora herself that I can go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no time for doubt only time for action. I must move this story forward and know that the time for timidity is over. I am not a boy hunting deer in the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My companions can do amazing and and terrible things with their weapons. I must do amazing and terrible things with the power of the Lady so that all may recognize me as her servant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be only boldness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/12/01/d-and-d-volume-1-8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/12/01/d-and-d-volume-1-8.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear Pennsylvania</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, Vote. Especially if you live in Pennsylvania. If you are registered in Pennsylvania, you should vote in person. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.votespa.com/Voting-in-PA/Pages/Voting-at-a-Polling-Place.aspx&quot;&gt;find a polling place here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help getting to the your polling place, call someone. If you are registered with a political party, call your county party office. They want you to vote and will help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pennsylvanians may decide this election and every vote cast in Pennsylvania matters and should be counted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I think you should vote for Joe Biden for President. I did. This is the first time I’ve supported a Democrat for President. I worked for &lt;a href=&quot;https://justfacts.votesmart.org/candidate/evaluations/27054/rick-santorum&quot;&gt;Senator Rick Santorum&lt;/a&gt;. I interned at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heritage.org/about-heritage/mission&quot;&gt;Heritage Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commonwealthfoundation.org/about/&quot;&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. I went to Grove &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gcc.edu/Home/Our-Story/Faith-Freedom&quot;&gt;City College&lt;/a&gt;. I am not a socialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 25, 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trumps-ukraine-call-transcript-read-the-document&quot;&gt;President Trump had a phone call with the President of Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s a lot of talk about Biden’s son, that Biden stopped the prosecution and a lot of people want to find out about that. So whatever you can do with the Attorney General would be great. Biden went around bragging that he stopped the prosecution so if you can look into it…It sounds horrible to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The President of the United States asked a foreign leader to investigate his opponent. This is not acceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if your kid, or niece, told you they asked some kids from the next town over to dig up dirt on the person they were running against for Class President. Would you be excited about that? Would that be behavior you encourage or discourage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect more from the President of the United States. I think you should as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/11/01/vote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/11/01/vote.html</guid>
        
        <category>vote</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-7</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wolf was the chief. The beast who made short work of two villagers before our eyes was the very man sworn to protect this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have we walked into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wanted us to protect this village, all the while he was hunting it? He needed us to stand up to a few dozen men, when he could turn into a fire breathing, ten foot tall, wolf?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something is not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our trade at the chapel in Vestygg was merchants barely getting through the door, tossing their coins into the basked my father had invented, and moving on. Our coffer basked took the time to ask the Lady’s favor from minutes to seconds, and the donations poured in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t all a volume business. There were the confessors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inaction is the only sin in the worship of the Lady. Moral codes of absolute right and wrong rarely work in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, one of Pelor’s sunnies can do ethical summersaults to prove that a woman is justified to steal bread to feed her starving children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ask the same summer priests what that same woman should do if she can only steal one loaf, but has two children and they freeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can a god tell someone there is a right choice in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tell her to break the loaf in half, and ask Tymora to be kind. Luck and chance sustain when goodness and mercy can not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The penitent would come to our chapel and confess their indecision. The Abbott would listen, and nod, and tell them what to do. Sometimes it was his best judgement, sometimes it was what they wanted to hear so he could go back to the tavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when someone was droning on for particularity long, and wasn’t keping the coppers dropping in the coffer, the Abbot would excuse himself come to my cell, and ask me to take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is why the first bit of wisdom he taught me was how to have the Lady transform me into someone else. It’s also why he taught me how to mimic voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would ask the Lady to make me look like the Abbott, check the mirror and walk back in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from a burden, these encounters were my only contact with the outside world. I would revel in the details. My aim was to ask the question that unlocked their indecision – like a key turning a bolt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how I knew something was wrong in this village. Why would only one specific hut, not on the edge of the village be attacked? Why one boy, but not another, why now? Who in the village could leave unseen when everyone shares their tent with others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked Shaba about that, she barely understood why. The chief is the only one that could come and go as he pleased, and apparently his pleasure was to hunt his kith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/09/28/d-and-d-volume-1-7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/09/28/d-and-d-volume-1-7.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-6</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize I have never been cold. When you grow up sharing a monk’s cell, even a small oil lamp will keep you warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fall, my father and I hunted for the deer that would keep us fed through the winter. Leaving before first light I could often see my breath, but I wasn’t cold. I was free. We would stay in the woods all day, butchering anything we would take, and wrapping it in paper so we could smuggle it back in after dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were long days, but not cold days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know cold now. As we trudge towards the village, the the stinging salt spray quickly coats my robes. If this place doesn’t give us shelter, we won’t make it through the day, let alone the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard of these islands of the far north, isolated, just the way the elves like it. Fortunately Kirrix and Elros speak elvish and secure us freedom to enter the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bargain for cloaks, but the reality is I would have given the coin from my forehead for the warmth these cloaks provide. Lady forgive me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly the next hour is a blur, we trudge up to see the leader of this village, tell him our lie, tell him the truth, and he doesn’t slit our throats. That is enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as I lay down in their infirmary I feel some measure of warmth. As I see the others fall off to sleep, I pull out the lockbox we found in the temple. I want desperately to hear that tune again, but I have on idea if opening the box here wil make the entire structure collapse around us. And I’m too tired to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I awaken to the chief telling us that few will stay and fight, and that blurry hour comes back to me. We’ve agreed to help this village fend off Lady Sky’s enforcers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m wanted in Ostia and Rudainia, why not add Kaldygg to the list! I have no more home, and Lady Sky is a tyrant. Let’s see what luck the true Lady can bring this village at the icy end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/09/21/d-and-d-volume-1-6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/09/21/d-and-d-volume-1-6.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-5</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bryce&quot;&gt;Bryce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We survived him. Another Black Knight has fallen and now we have the phylactery, whatever that is. I’m not even sure if the Knight thing was alive before it stopped moving, but we once again have ended something’s existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t my path. I have been bouncing from inn to inn, battle, to negotiation, to battle, but for what? I don’t seek fortune or fame. I have no grudge with these people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I do have now is an object of immense power and value. And I know that the object is desired by someone in the court at Rausten&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning and plotting as Kirrix and I walk back in the library to be greeted by 20 crossbowman, a priest, and some Rudainian high nobel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like the law has caught up to us. We dash back into the sanctuary of the Library and fling the door shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately the key I picked up in the library seems to lock the doors with some arcane magic so we have tome to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have no ideas, there is no way out of this room, and while we may be able to bottle them up in the door, eventually we will be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do have the lockbox. We have no idea what’s in it, but we know that the combination was found in a book about demonic planar binding. That doesn’t bode well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set the lockbox in front of the threshold and wait for the door to fling open. After his dip in the black starry ooze, Kirrix, has some new abilities and dials the combination from across the room as the door flings open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead of a demon appearing a simple tune plays. I lower my bow. I know this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a memory that is familiar and foreign all at the same time. Like something that was willed into my memory. But the memory is so caring. I feel so safe, so loved. More loved than I have since I was thrust out of the chapel back in Vestygg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tune ends too soon a deep rumble begins and the floor shifts under my feet. The black ooze is bubbling and expanding. Without a word, we all know it’s time to leave. I follow my companions out the door and see chaos on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take the time to pick up the box and take a look back at where the statue of Sariel Silvertree once stood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pompous priest of Pelor is encouraging his brethren to continue the fight. I hop on the table with him and humbly suggest that neither Pelor nor the Lady will be getting anyone out of this mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I run down the table and get to the door, I see Walter stumbling. We left him behind. My stomach sinks as the Lady gives my voice strength to tell Walter to jump on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He does and the damned priest tries to stop him. These Divine Brotherhood bastards don’t know when to quit. As Walter tries to free himself from the priest grasp they both tumble into the abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Library continues to collapse around us I don’t have time to think more about our lost friend. We clamber back up into the tall tower and everything feels more stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose to go through the door that we think takes us to the North. We step into the snow, wrap our cloaks around us and begin to trudge to some smoke we see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are on the run. Most who know of us are dead, but not all. We have an object powerful enough to take life with a touch. Desired by other worldly Knights and members of the royal court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen merchants toss dozens of coins into my offering plate asking for the Lady to bring them fortune. But not even toss a copper to the beggars on their way out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lady doesn’t make the rich. Anymore than Beshaba makes the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luck is sewn throughout the World without much care. What we do with that fortune is the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have some fortune. The Lady favors the bold. Maybe we can turn the world on its head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volume 1-4 was skipped because it was just combat. Not the most fun to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/31/d-and-d-volume-1-5.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/31/d-and-d-volume-1-5.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-3</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pelor&quot;&gt;Pelor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brigand did well to replace Alhandra’s holy medallion. I’m surprised he did knowing his penchant for trinkets. That boy priest looks to have talked sense in to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where have I seen this Lady worshiper before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said you wanted the box, not what was in it.” He said as he handed it over. What a clever boy. I usually don’t allow such acts of insolence to my faithful, but this band of the Divine Brotherhood throw my name around like a cheap parlor trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few hours earlier those idiots fleeced some bigger idiot Rudainians. The reversal pleased me. This boy priest has won my blessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not often my eye lingers on the material plane, but to see Alhandra, my faithful servant, picked apart by that abomination of an abomination. Such a forsaken place devoid of any true light, mired in darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did these survive when my champion had fallen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello there!” the brigand greets a dead elf. It’s amazing to me these fools got the door open but they did. I can’t imagine how their puny brains can comprehend the portals they uncovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I open my mind and can be anywhere. I can see each of them born, dead, reborn. I can jump to any point in their story, or any place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for them to be able to step through a doorway and be thousands of miles away. Oh it’s such a joy to see their smug faces smacked with a bit of the impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They made short work of the Owlbear that fell Alhandra. Although they could have avoided it entirely if the Weaver hadn’t been going on about his eyes, or lack thereof. Seemed an odd moment for story time, but I don’t pretend to understand humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Them seem to have no fear of the dark abomination that floods the sanctuary. I can’t even gaze at it without feeling sick. It’s the complete absence of light, everything I stand for, everting I am for this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way my light brings justice to everything it touches, this darkness brings corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The darwf reduced to a skelton surrounded by a gelatinous mass of pure nothingness. They fought that with such abandon. How lucky they are they do not know the evil that fuels these foul beasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brigand has done well. There will come a time when he will call on me and I will answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lady may bring luck, but I bring the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/09/d-and-d-volume-1-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/09/d-and-d-volume-1-3.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volume 1-2</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;walter&quot;&gt;Walter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done what I can for them, and they hardly take notice. The uneven rocking of the boat tells me that we have yet to cross the river, but what’s troubling is not what I feel under my bones, but what I can’t smell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reek as we’ve left Flod hasn’t given way to salt air or decaying reed grasses. It’s as if we are sailing off the edge of the map. I can hear water lapping on the shore, but no scent of wood in water or drying fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat bumps to a halt, and I’m clumsily helped out on to the shore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally a smell, though not a pleasant one. Poorly butchered meat and salt. This place is not in ballance, not connected. Silent. It’s not just Rudainia that has gone silent but the great five pointed web itself has cessed to vibrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some meaningless banter and an exchange of some bobble for information gave my adventuring companions enough courage to cross the river. But no one asks me what I think, and I’m so far from home I don’t have much choice but to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trudge through a root infested path and then out onto unkempt cobble stones when I can feel a breeze and with it the first hint of life. Forest, alive, but not living. Ripe with decay and malice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently we come to a gap in a bridge and I’m unceremoniously lowered onto two ropes and told to shuffle across by my armpits. I slip half way through and while they debate about how they might help me up, I right myself. I’m blind, not helpless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel the space close in and the smell of the forest deepens, we slow and I hear a new voice hoarsely calling, I can’t make it out, sounds like names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cocky one, Bryce, whispers in my ear, “What do you smell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smug little bastard. He thinks he’s smarter than everyone, but he knows nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tell him, “the forest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He brings me closer to the new voice, and as I lean in, I feel a spongy hand on my chest and suddenly I’m thrust 10 feet backward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there the usual sounds of slashing and stabbing. These men and half-elves have little imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A arrow whistles and the forest comes alive. I lack the vocabulary to describe the language of the trees, but I can smell their now angry breath on the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear a the crack of a whip, and then another and Bryce cries out. A smash of glass and then heat and the sound of cracking, smoking wet wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve made our way to the door of this place, but it has announced we are not welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently playing through a campaign DM’d by the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://erikmaxwell.co/&quot;&gt;Erik Maxwell&lt;/a&gt;. As a writing exercise I’m giving myself 30 minutes to recap our weekly adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/04/d-and-d-vol-1-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2020/08/04/d-and-d-vol-1-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>d&amp;d</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
