<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shoe in the Door</title>
    <description>Helping organizations tell their story and expand their reach.</description>
    <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://shoeinthedoor.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:18:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:18:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>WordCamp Seattle 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my second year at WordCamp and I’m excited to learn more about creating content and this thing called Gutenberg? Perhaps you’ve heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I take notes, so any errors are likely mine not the speaker. I’ll be updating this as we go through the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keynote-bridget-willard--community-observe-include-accept&quot;&gt;Keynote: Bridget Willard – Community: Observe, Include, Accept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridget is from Orange County. And is Orange County excited for a Seattle crowd. At 9am. On a Saturday. It’s difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community is not just a noun, it’s a verb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are all just working on a group project like it’s 4th grade – and sometimes we fight like it too&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are wired to be connected to each other, and when we are deprived of that connection it affects us spiritually, emotionally, physically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It’s so illegally cold in Minnesota”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“If you keep talking, I’m going to call on you, because I have a great view.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Did you know that these are all your friends? Sometimes it just helps to hear it.” Life happens to people (tell me about it), we need to hold each other in those times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nouns have no meaning, if the behavior doesn’t go with it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We like to think we make logical decisions, but we make emotional decisions and reverse engineer the logic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We can’t build this thing called WordPress if we all think the same.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our computers are de-humanizing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s really talking about hospitality, which is a core value of Christianity (at least as I practice it). It is fascinating to hear someone basically preach on The Sermon on the Mount, but from a totally secular perspective. Observe, Include, and Accept as core values are values of the WordPress community and of the Christian community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that may come as a surprise, based on how Christianity is practiced in the United States today, but for me, and my community it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andrew-taylor---the-benefits-of-testing-and-automation&quot;&gt;Andrew Taylor - The Benefits of Testing and Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a maintainer of websites. We pick up projects and we have to keep them going over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe there is a better way than shoving everything on a staging site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead if you test continuously, after every change less messes to detangle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checking things you didn’t work on is boring, time consuming, and hard to bill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated testing is the road less traveled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual regression as baseline - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/garris/BackstopJ&quot;&gt;Backstop JS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examining performance - &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse/&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automated testing is important in WordPress, but even more important with the work I’m doing at &lt;a href=&quot;http;//webconnex.com&quot;&gt;WebConnex&lt;/a&gt;. Implementing visual regression testing is on my list to get started on day 1, the performance testing will actually be a bit easier to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jonathan-peck---the-other-wpml-machine-learning--ai-in-wordpress&quot;&gt;Jonathan Peck - The other WPML: Machine Learning / Ai in WordPress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advocate for &lt;a href=&quot;https://algorithmia.com/&quot;&gt;Algorithmia&lt;/a&gt;, which does Machine Learning hosting. What follows are ideas for how we could use this at WebConnex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recommender engine - show the right race length&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI based, dynamic ambassador discount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use tweet sentiment to figure out how people feel about the event&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team name/GroupRev suggestion based on past performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suggestion on fields to add/remove based on performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object detection for alt tags of images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text summarization for meta descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated statement images for social media (Cloudinary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talked walked a fine line between pitch and information. I think it ended up fairly pitchy, but the service looks helpful, so I care a bit less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taylor-waldon---making-content-part-of-company-culture&quot;&gt;Taylor Waldon - Making Content Part of Company Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor has been doing content since college working at a food service company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic permission marketing thinking create: relevant, timely, expected&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are creating the content out of the final publishing medium, you need to re-edit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Content Matrix&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Value&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Key Message&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Key Message&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog Post Template
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;title&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;author&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;category&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;image direction&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;target audience&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;offer/value&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;keyword&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;hook/meta description&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule, free Google calendar if you need more &lt;a href=&quot;https://coschedule.com/&quot;&gt;CoSchedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was done in 20 minutes. It was actually a significantly dense introduction to content management. As someone immersed in that world for years it was helpful. If I were brand new, I don’t think I would have gotten as much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bob-dunn---how-to-repurpose-a-single-piece-of-content-into-a-lot-of-content&quot;&gt;Bob Dunn - How to Repurpose a Single Piece of Content Into a Lot of Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned a camera on for this session and counted people there were 90 people +/- 5 at this session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internal links give Google a roadmap for your website, basically pillar pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating content is the biggest way he grows his traffic
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tweaks: add content, links to newer posts, but all in context&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turns: revive or bury posts, deleting is the easy way with redirect, harder way is to rethink&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Twists: save as draft, rewrite, and schedule&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up links as post title (no dates in URL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use audio and video (duh), turn audio into videoless video, less duh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/polly/&quot;&gt;Amazon Polly&lt;/a&gt; to transcribe text posts to audio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extractions: Inverviews, tips, lists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One post serves all
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Monday: email list&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tuesday: blog&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wednesday: talking head video&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thursday: podcast&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When re-using content make sure to use canonical URLs for your extractions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He’s tried time and again to make money from his most popular blog post, but he just can’t - he just makes people happy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good reminder to look at content after it’s published and re-link it to more modern content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devin-walker---if-you-build-it-right-they-will-come--creating-truly-valuable-wordpress-products-and-services&quot;&gt;Devin Walker - If You Build It (Right), They Will Come – Creating Truly Valuable WordPress Products and Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devin works for Give WP. He started his talk going through a bunch of different business models from freelancer to large company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking about Why first &lt;a href=&quot;https://startwithwhy.com/&quot;&gt;Start with Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GiveWP’s mission is to democratize generosity, so you don’t have to pay a SaaS provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are both product and service opportunities on top of WordPress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GiveWP started as a services company that was building nonprofit sites and was hacking together a donation solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advocating functional specs, I’m not a fan, I say build the thing ala 37Signals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your idea is a car, don’t start with a wheel, start with a scooter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how true the “If you build it they will come” message is for WordPress tools. The overall, measured, systematic approach to starting a business Devin set out does mean success is more likely, but not assured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andrea-zoellner---storytelling-with-gutenberg-how-to-use-the-new-editor-to-boost-your-blog&quot;&gt;Andrea Zoellner - Storytelling with Gutenberg: How to Use the New Editor to Boost Your Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrea is an end user, so she focused on content creation and is excited about Gutenberg as was Taylor, another content creator. It’s probably a good sign for WordPress. There are way more content creators using WordPress than developers. Developers are likely much louder voices, but the creators will win out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Referencing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall/index.html#/?part=tunnel-creek&quot;&gt;Snowfall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nearly 1/3 of visitors to page were new to the NY Times&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“With Gutenberg anyone can Snowfall”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gutenberg tips&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add styles to your text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diversify your images - use gallery to display 3- or 4-up feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrate other post types, Adding shortcodes is easier, but still not as easy as if the shortcode became a block&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add multi-media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add breathing room, much better than adding a bunch of empty spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in a call to action, button blocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify your workflow, re-usable blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very clear that for 95 percent of things you don’t need commercial themes anymore. I’ve long been an advocate of lean, performant custom themes, but Gutenberg makes that argument that much more compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robert-nissenbaum---a-hypothesis-on-the-future-impact-of-gutenberg-on-seo&quot;&gt;Robert Nissenbaum - A Hypothesis on the Future Impact of Gutenberg on SEO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s not a developer. So all this hullabaloo doesn’t matter as much to him. His theory as to “Why Gutenberg?” How we consume content is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile is continuing to increase both as a percentage of traffic and time on site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If how content is consumed changes, how we publish has to change as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve done it at the macro level, now we have to think about the micro-content level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The web and WordPress isn’t going to be about pages, it’s about blocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If Yoast (our default SEO tool) thinks about pages, how do we make it think about blocks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if we did SEO on individual blocks?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perhaps the media library is a cue as to a future content block library&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe this can be a way to avoid duplicate content, so that Google understands the atomic pieces of content are re-used but the particular composition is unique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting theory, but I’m not sold. Google can’t figure out what a “block” is, unless it’s served as part of a sitemap.xml somehow. It would seem a very large shift from Google to not think about the document as the base unit of the internet. Especially since that’s how individuals consume content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see why Google would want to go this way. If we allow Google to serve individual blocks, out of context, then people are using Google not our sites. It’s like the worst of AMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do agree that thinking this way will get you better content, so it’s sensible on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jocelyn-mozak---clone-yourself-through-automation&quot;&gt;Jocelyn Mozak - Clone Yourself Through Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jocelyn is an agency owner and she talked about how she worked on automation in her own business. Specifically looking at how she uses automation in the sales process and onboarding process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Automation is a mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replies to requests for a website with a questionnaire and a link to schedule a meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At each step she is sending people to her email marketing and tagging people based on actions and sending automated emails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can’t automate the sales call and proposal, but can automate getting the proposal signed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow-ups through while the proposal is about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once signed, automated email and then back to scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using Gravity forms and Zapier to auto create accounts in multiple software platfoms (Slack, accounting, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the project, tag the client to automatically ask for testimonials or sell maintenance plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jacob-smith---from-developer-to-entrepreneur&quot;&gt;Jacob Smith - From Developer to Entrepreneur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh wait that’s me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shoeinthedoor.com/files/WordCamp-Seattle-2018-JacobWSmith-Presentation.pdf&quot;&gt;Here are the slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/11/10/wordcamp-seattle-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/11/10/wordcamp-seattle-2018.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adults Prefer The Box Too</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s cliche to say that kids prefer to play in the box the fancy thing came in. But it’s true. A quick bit of internet searching turns up no academic papers on the subject. So as an armchair psychologist and expert struggling learning parent of a 7-month old, I have some thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;boxes-are-familiar&quot;&gt;Boxes are FAMILIAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your kid has been sleeping in a box their whole life. In fact, the very first object they were placed in, was very boxlike. They know how the box works, they know how to interact with it, and they know it’s safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If fits tidily into their growing mental model of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this changes as you grow up, you are sadly mistaken. In his recent book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldcat.org/title/unpersuadables-adventures-with-the-enemies-of-science/oclc/852222088/&quot;&gt;The Unpersuadables: Adventures with the Enemies of Science&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; Will Storr talks with young earth creationists, holocaust deniers, and homeopathic medicine advocates. He finds they all exhibit similar symptoms of confirmation bias. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirmation bias is the tendency to cherry pick facts that support your previously held beliefs and ignore facts that are problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you are thinking this is a problem for other people, Storr has some other thoughts. He claims we all do this. And it’s a survival tactic. He uses the phrase &lt;em&gt;superabundance of information&lt;/em&gt; to describe the vast amount of information out there. Our brains have evolved to filter out extraneous information. When you are being chased by a lion, your brain doesn’t need to be distracted wondering what type of flower you just stepped on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for both your toddler and you, the familiar, the objects, concepts, opinions, and ideas that fit nicely into your current narrative are the most attractive. And by magnitudes we strengthen that narrative, making it harder for new information to break in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;boxes-are-open-ended&quot;&gt;Boxes are open ended&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toy inside the box has some opinions about how you use it. If you immediately turn it upside down, a well meaning parent is going to “fix” it for you. But when you flip the box, it just went from a car to a tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still remember reading the manual when I bought the original Sim City. Gather round and hear about when you went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EB_Games&quot;&gt;Electronics Boutique&lt;/a&gt; and purchased software that came in a box. Back then, it also came with a manual and the manual for Sim City did not call it a computer “game,” it called it a  computer “toy.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manual went on to say a ball is a toy, it can be used in any number of games, just like Sim City. Want to be an urban planner extraordinaire, go right ahead. Want to put that nuclear power plant right next to a park, sounds great. Want to rebuild 1961 Tokyo after a &lt;a href=&quot;http://simcity.wikia.com/wiki/Tokyo,_1961&quot;&gt;monster attack&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In _The Unpersuadables&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;_Storr also posits that we all want to be the hero of our own story. Open ended interactions let you write the story with you at its center. Not so with a flashing, beeping, attention-grabbing toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-this-applies-to-marketing-how&quot;&gt;And this applies to marketing How?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you are saying, “Fascinating, musings, really blue-sky solutioneering here, but I have a TPS report cover sheet that needs attention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you think about the content you are creating, consider these two questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does this fit into my audience’s established mode of thinking?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does this allow my audience to be the hero of the story?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer to either of those questions is no, your content isn’t going to find the traction you are hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/adults-prefer-the-box-too&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/09/24/adults-prefer-the-box-too.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/09/24/adults-prefer-the-box-too.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get Honesty By Being Negative</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve interviewed a fair number of folks in my years. Not just for jobs, but possible vendors as well. We also do interviews as part of our branding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the middle of reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldcat.org/title/unpersuadables-adventures-with-the-enemies-of-science/oclc/881888141&amp;amp;referer=brief_results&quot;&gt;The Unpersuadables&lt;/a&gt;, which talks a lot about how our brains are set up to lie to us, even when we are trying to be truthful. This makes interviews problematic. People generally want to present a positive view of themselves and the world, so they are unlikely to admit the negative side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90221337/how-to-phrase-interview-questions-to-get-people-to-tell-the-truth&quot;&gt;University of Utah study&lt;/a&gt; suggests a tricky phrasing to elicit an honest response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example, instead of asking, “Do you ever use work time for personal email or social media?” or “Have you used a sick day when you weren’t actually sick?” VanEpps suggests phrasing your question with the negative assumption. “‘You’ve used a sick day when you weren’t sick, right? Or ‘You use work time for personal email, right?’ ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They did find this only works with common behaviors. Asking something like, “You do steal other employee’s lunches, right?” would be a bridge too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes some sense, by normalizing the potentially negative behavior you have created space for conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In brand interviews we often ask about negative interactions. Rather than asking, “Can you think of a time where your interactions with Brand X weren’t ideal?” this research would suggest we should ask, “We’ve heard about some not ideal interactions with Brand X, can you tell me one you have had?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are social animals. By making the interviewee’s negative actions part of the group, it allows them to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the honest truth is we all do some personal emailing at work, have taken sick days because we just wanted a day off, and have had at least one less than ideal interaction with a brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all of those cases an honest answer is always better than a flat denial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/get-honesty-by-being-negative&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/08/30/get-honesty-by-being-negative.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/08/30/get-honesty-by-being-negative.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eye-tracking the Abstract</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Artwork is inherently emotional and the emotional reactions that are elicited by abstract artwork might lead participants to focus their attention within the upper-right quadrant to better engage emotional processing”&lt;br /&gt;
— Nicole Thomas and Ali Simpson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/322581891_Neuroticism_schizotypy_and_scale_anchors_influence_eye_movement_behaviour_in_the_visual_exploration_of_abstract_art_An_exploratory_study&quot;&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this article in Fast Company and was fascinated. We have used mouse tracking (a cheap alternative) on usability testing, but the thought of eye tracking in abstract art is new to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the pieces that was used was &lt;a href=&quot;https://nestortoro.com/sold-faces-blue-abstract-art-los-angeles/&quot;&gt;Faces of Blue&lt;/a&gt; by Nestor Toro. We used it for our feature image. I have no idea if Toro wanted to create a focal point or not, but I can see how different people may take it in differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic rule of thumb for web usability is that people scan from left to right in an “F” pattern. Two horizontal passes at the top of the page and then a longer vertical pass down the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study found a very different pattern. People started in the top right and moved around the painting in a clockwise motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interestingly they found people who where more neurotic focused more on the left side of the art. Nueroticsm is one of the “big five” personality traits and is defined this way by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologistworld.com/personality/neuroticism-personality-trait&quot;&gt;Psychologist World&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A neurotic personality is characterised by persistent, often disproportionate, worrying and anxiety. A person may strive to be a perfectionist during their everyday activities, and experience stress as a result of events that are beyond their control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors theorize that neuroticism causes people to focus inward and engage less with visual stimuli so they might not engage with the entire piece of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could think more about user’s emotional states more. We are working on a website for a humane society currently. It makes me think we need to consider how the emotional state of having to surrender an animal impacts design and user interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where else does emotion come into play in design?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/eye-tracking-the-abstract&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/07/31/eye-tracking-the-abstract.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/07/31/eye-tracking-the-abstract.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Software HubSpot vs. WordPress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise that we think WordPress is the greatest. Why then, have we migrated this blog and those of our clients to HubSpot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HubSpot is the best inbound marketing platform. The tools it has around lead capture and marketing automation are second to none. Your blog is a vital part of your inbound strategy and it makes sense to house it all in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not all sunshine and roses, but it is the right choice for most our clients. Here are our thoughts on HubSpot’s blog software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good&quot;&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content creation process is better out of the box on HubSpot. You can create draft posts and send a link to reviewers to be able to comment, no log in necessary. This is possible with plugins on WordPress, but not nearly as easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other boon is integrated reporting. You can see how your blog contributes to site traffic and lead generation all in a single spot. What gets measured gets managed and integrated reporting is key for properly managing your program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wouldn’t feel comfortable compromising on design. The HubSpot templating language can take some getting used to, but it does the job. We can implement the same high quality designs on either platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, HubSpot offers dead simple RSS to email subscriptions: no plugins, no API connects to troubleshoot. And HubSpot allows people to subscribe daily, weekly, and monthly. By allowing users to decide how often they get emails, you increase engagement and retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bad&quot;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HubSpot only offers tags for taxonomy. There is no ability for hierarchy. For many blogs this isn’t an issue. But if you had hundreds of posts, allowing for filtering on multiple fronts could be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only export option is CSV. That’s not the greatest, but it’s better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ugly&quot;&gt;The Ugly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog search is still in Beta. It’s a bit baffling that search isn’t something that was a version 1.0 feature, but it wasn’t. We’ve been using the Beta search with a few clients and it works well, but still is a bit of a pain to set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress search has it’s own foibles, but you get a lot of points for showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do have to host the blog on a subdomain. This really should go into “The Indifferent” category. It used to be that you would lose domain authority by having your blog on a subdomain. Current wisdom holds that search engines are smart enough to know there isn’t much of a difference between blog.abravenew.com and abravenew.com/blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-choice-for-you&quot;&gt;The Best Choice For You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving your blog to HubSpot isn’t always going to be the best choice. But if you looking to run a highly functioning inbound program on HubSpot it probably is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do have to be smart about migration and setting up proper redirects. You can expect to see a dip in your page rank, but the long term gains you will see with a more robust content program will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most technology decisions, the right choice for your company requires taking the time really dig into how you will be using the technology. Our rule of thumb: if you are using HubSpot, your blog should be on HubSpot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/blog-software-hubspot-vs.-wordpress&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/07/17/blog-software-hubspot-vs.-wordpress.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/07/17/blog-software-hubspot-vs.-wordpress.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Round Up Your Users</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Seattle has been invaded by a Skittles cornucopia of free-floating bikes. If you aren’t familiar with the concept, it’s a new way to do bike sharing in a city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional method has been to have docks around the city where you have to start and stop your ride. If you want to go where the docks are - great. If you want to go somewhere else, you are out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new free-floating bikes can be dropped off anywhere in the city limits, greatly expanding the ridable area. It’s been a &lt;a href=&quot;../../../com/abravenew/blog/3-keys-to-a-high-converting-email.html&quot;&gt;big success&lt;/a&gt;. There have been hiccups with people parking bikes in odd places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Baxpq9ojaU2/&quot;&gt;A post shared by Victor Balta (@victorbalta)&lt;/a&gt; on Oct 27, 2017 at 7:59pm PDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dock based system failed. It wasn’t that people didn’t want to ride shared bikes in Seattle. It is that they didn’t want to ride to a specific dock. They wanted to set the destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-website-is-a-bike-dock&quot;&gt;your website is a bike Dock&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your website is a specific destination on the Internet. We can drive traffic to your website, it’s what we do. And we do it well. We’ve grown businesses using tried and true web development and inbound techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if your customers have to visit your website for you to deliver value, you are limiting your potential growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;home-on-the-internet-range&quot;&gt;Home on the (Internet) range&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your users are spread over the vast range of the Internet. They are on Facebook, or Google Maps, or Amazon. Are you there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not just with ads, but with a your core offering allowing them to transact wherever they are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s daunting to think about keeping all your information up to date in all these places. Believe it or not, that’s where a well built website comes to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These third party services want your data. They need it to make their service valuable. But your data has to get there. You could create everything multiple times and update data in a dozen places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you could strategically use your website as the source for all these third party sites. The specifics on how to do this are unique to your business, but we have a few good questions to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Identify your endpoints&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Do you need to sell your product on Amazon? Do your hours need to show up in Yelp? Do your blog posts need to be published to LinkedIn? Make a list of all the places your customers currently are and what information needs to go there. If your not sure where to start, look at your fiercest competitor. Where are they? You should be there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**2. Describe the data&lt;br /&gt;
**What data does each service need? Chances are once you list this for each service you will see overlap where one piece of data is needed by multiple services. If you map this back to your content strategy (you have a &lt;a href=&quot;../../../com/abravenew/blog/having-a-strategy-for-your-content-matters.html&quot;&gt;content strategy&lt;/a&gt;, right?) you will find which data exists and where you have gaps in your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**3. Research how endpoints access data&lt;br /&gt;
**Some sites require submission of data, others can read it from your website if you structure the data properly. There is likely overlap here as well. For example, Facebook and Twitter use open graph tags. If you implement those tags for one service, you get the other one for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**4. Connect the Dots&lt;br /&gt;
**You know where you want your data to go and what data needs to go there. Now you have to connect the dots. If you are using an open source CMS, like say WordPress, you are in luck. There are plugins to connect WordPress to just about anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need great metadata? &lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/wordpress/plugins/seo/&quot;&gt;Yoast SEO&lt;/a&gt; has you covered. Want to sell on WooCommerce and other retailers? &lt;a href=&quot;https://woocommerce.com/products/product-retailers/&quot;&gt;No problem&lt;/a&gt;. And if the integration doesn’t exist, the REST API can make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-you-build-it-they-will-not-come&quot;&gt;if you build it they will not come&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is what we do, so it’s no surprise when we say you have to do more than just build a website. You need to be advertising and doing SEO and PR and inbound marketing and getting your data to where your users are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your users are ranging all over the internet. If your content isn’t, then you are missing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/round-up-your-users&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/20/round-up-your-users.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/20/round-up-your-users.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcast Get off Your Phone!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you used your phone in a meeting? Have you? What if your boss ‘lost it’ and demanded all phones are banned in meeting. Well that happened and was reported in  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JimBourke/status/996760027087155200&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from the Wall Street Journal. Excuse the link to a twitter status to avoid the WSJ paywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen as Josh, Jacob and Polly discuss how we use phones at A Brave New, how to create interesting meetings, and how to eat Skittles during a podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/get-off-your-phone&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/13/get-off-your-phone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/13/get-off-your-phone.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UTM Parameters the Brave New Way</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have never heard of UTM Parameters you are not alone. If you are thinking you know all there is to know, you are equally in good company. We’ve put together simple, proven steps to a healthy Google Analytics setup. This post synthesizes the combined knowledge of dozens of years of experience and hundreds of campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UTM parameters are extra strings added to a URL. You can read about them &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1033863#parameters&quot;&gt;specifically here&lt;/a&gt;. There are dozens of blog posts on how to set them up, but none that detail how we do it. We think our setup works well across a bunch of different campaigns, so please do steal away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t going to cover the basics, so if this is all new to you, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UTM_parameters&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; is a good primer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-dos-and-donts&quot;&gt;General Do’s and Dont’s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; use utm_source, utm_medium, and utm_campaign. It’s important to use all three.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T&lt;/strong&gt; use utm_keyword for anything but keywords. Some people use it for other bits of data, but it gets confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; add utm parameters to outbound email links, social advertising, organic social, bing, just about anything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T&lt;/strong&gt; add utm parameters to AdWords (Google does it automatically) or links on your website (this will result in over counting some stats and undercounting others, it’s a bad scene).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; use a consistent naming convention. More on that below.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T&lt;/strong&gt; use spaces or special characters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; keep track of your parameters. In a sheet &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1n8zVZUPFK88ELGm8UCUQWq0A65FIKjNbULt821gZebs/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt; one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;utm_medium&quot;&gt;utm_medium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look at medium as the biggest funnel. Here are the mediums we generally use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;social&lt;/strong&gt; - for &lt;em&gt;organic&lt;/em&gt; social posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;email&lt;/strong&gt; - for email, both automated and traditional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cpc&lt;/strong&gt; - for non-AdWords paid search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cpp&lt;/strong&gt; - for paid Social&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;display&lt;/strong&gt; - for non-AdWords display&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;affiliate&lt;/strong&gt; - for link shares, guest blog posts, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use these mediums to fit into Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/3297892?hl=en&quot;&gt;default channel definitions&lt;/a&gt;. It makes reporting in Google Analytics (where all this data ends up) much cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only interesting one is cpp for paid Social. We chose that to direct that traffic into the “Other Advertising” channel. We have no idea what cpp stands for, so we aren’t worried about data collisions with other mediums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could have kept the medium “social,” but we were finding it was difficult to differentiate paid efforts when we had an integrated campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;utm_source&quot;&gt;utm_source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The middle of the funnel is source. This one gets more specialized by client and medium. In social (both paid and organic) we use the name of the network. Same thing with ad networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In email, we often use an audience name for traditional one-to-many emails and a more generic type for automated one-to-one emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example if you send a monthly email to all customers, we might use “customers” as the source. If we have a follow up email stream after a white paper download, we would use “whitepaper” or “resource.” New donor steams might use “welcome.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, you have one more level with utm_campaign. Think about how you would want to roll up your reporting and group similar emails with utm_source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;utm_campaign&quot;&gt;utm_campaign&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most granular level is campaign. This should clearly identify the individual effort and be shared across sources and mediums. That’s the real power of utm_parameters. To be able to both report by campaign and by channel and in combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are very client specific. We’ve used “newcustomer” “deardonor” “may2018” to name just a few. You do have a decision here if your campaigns are run annually or even several times a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you have an annual campaign called “Power of One.” That campaign name could be “powerofone” or “powerofone2018.” We wouldn’t suggest “powerofone18” as it’s not immediately clear that 18 is a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By adding the year you make it easy to report on annual results regardless of the timeframe selected, but more difficult to report across years. We do it both ways, but our preference is to not include the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;utm_content&quot;&gt;utm_content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember when I said that utm_campaign was the most granular? Well not exactly. We use utm_content in a few specific situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When we are running a test to differentiate test panels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When we have a multi-email automated stream to differentiate between messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it, we don’t use it often, but it can come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-word-about-testing&quot;&gt;A Word About Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to test your utm parameters to make sure they are set up properly. Fortunately, Google Analytic’s real time reporting includes a report by campaign. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vSIisd_ZvM&quot;&gt;great video&lt;/a&gt; on how to do this. Please excuse the intro music and the use of a delta as an “A”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;train-the-team&quot;&gt;Train the Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least, you have to train your team (and maybe a partner or two) on your conventions and rules. Without shared understanding about how things are done, you can get into hot water fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have come round to these methods after years of learning. But we know there are smart people reading this, so share your favorite utm tip or trick in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/utm-parameters-the-brave-new-way&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/05/utm-parameters-the-brave-new-way.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/06/05/utm-parameters-the-brave-new-way.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be Unpredictable And Be Loved</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent conversation about sleep training, my sister mentioned that going in to her kids’ rooms sometimes and not others is a form of random reinforcement that has can prove to be the most effective at encouraging them to cry to get your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an odd finding. You would think going in every time would make them cry to get you in there, but it’s not. You can look up B.F. Skinners &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplypsychology.org/operant-conditioning.html&quot;&gt;original research&lt;/a&gt; or any number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/brain-wise/201311/use-unpredictable-rewards-keep-behavior-going&quot;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want to see the dark side of the topic, read about &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.mit.edu/2009/vegas-tt0520&quot;&gt;slot machines&lt;/a&gt;. They program players to play until they run out of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, our brains are very “hackable.” We predictably respond to rewards and certain reward schedules are better at establishing and maintaining behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far too often in our customer (or donor) appreciation programs we do the same thing every time. It’s easier to manage programs if they are standardized across everyone. But the research shows we should be doing four things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-keep-doing-the-basics&quot;&gt;1. Keep Doing the Basics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still need to be sending receipts and and thank-you’s after every transaction. You want a baseline of interaction that people can expect. That doesn’t mean the default language that comes out of your software is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These messages are important brand communicators. Take time to audit your receipt email. Does it sound like your organization? Are the special benefits of being a customer highlighted? Are you genuinely thankful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially important for nonprofits. You simply have to thank donors after every transaction. It should be immediate and personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-add-in-the-random&quot;&gt;2. Add in the Random&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, create five to six random rewards to sprinkle in. These could be phone calls, coupons, special extras in shipments, social media shout outs. It’s another great chance to align to your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part is systematizing this randomness. The Skinner experiments used a variable ratio of rewards to actions. In other words, you reward people on average every three transactions, but not every third transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after 9 transactions someone should have 3 rewards, but they may have gotten them after transactions 2, 3 and 7. But wait, that schedule rewards two reactions in a row? Yes - in fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://numbergenerator.org/pick3randomnumbers#!numbers=3&amp;amp;low=1&amp;amp;high=9&amp;amp;unique=true&amp;amp;start=false&quot;&gt;random numbers&lt;/a&gt; sometimes don’t appear random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you do this at scale? Don’t worry about being exact. Pick a day of the week that is reward day. Each reward day select a random sample of transactions to give the reward for that week. Next week, move the reward day forward a day, and pick a new reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How big of a sample do you need? It depends on the reward. Pick a sample size as large as you can actually execute. Easy rewards, like a coupon code, can go to a larger set, more personal rewards, a smaller set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry about any transaction to reward ratio at this point. Without data, you have no idea where to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-make-people-think-they-just-missed-the-jackpot&quot;&gt;3. Make People Think They Just Missed the Jackpot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another lesson from slot machines. For the unfamiliar, slot machines used to have a number of wheels with icons on them. The wheels would spin and you could stop them and try to line up similar icons on the pay line. The pay line was a physical line on the glass of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video slots keep all these visual ideas, but without those pesky physical wheels. The machine can easily make it look like you just “missed” the jackpot. Of course it’s fiction. The machine selects the pay line icons and then assigns the others. It could randomly assign them, but why would you do that when you can make people think they just missed a huge payout?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also see this in shipping minimums on ecommerce. You are so close to free shipping, if you just add $3 to your cart. Good luck finding a $3 item. After you have added that $12 pair of socks to your cart you can save the $5 shipping charge. Don’t do the math, it isn’t pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an area where social communities really come in handy. When you are dropping something special in the mail, tag the customer in a tweet or Facebook post. Letting the whole community know about who is receiving rewards makes people wonder how they might get the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-start-tracking&quot;&gt;4. Start Tracking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buzzkill. Handing out goodies is great, but you need to start tracking right away. You need to know which customers have been rewarded and with what rewards. After a few months you can look at the data and see if those customers are more valuable. Be brutal, if it isn’t working be ready to switch it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also be able to calculate the most efficient reward to transaction ratio. Now you can get a bit more systemized about your reward selection. Say you find that the average ratio of your most valuable customers is one reward per five transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would export all transactions in the last week of anyone who has between 2 and 7 total transactions and no rewards, as well as anyone who has one reward and between 5 and 12 transactions, and so on. That’s your universe and you can then apply your rewards to make sure you cover everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also be able to see if particular rewards are better performing. But don’t standardize, the whole point is they are random. Drop the lowest performing two and create variations of the best. We aren’t going for pure efficiency here. You need a large number of possible rewards if you are going to make it feel random to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-be-evil&quot;&gt;Don’t Be Evil&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In interviews, slots players have said they choose dark pants so they don’t have to stop playing to walk to the bathroom. That’s how far a random rewards system can bend behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your rewards program reinforces your brand and is customer (or donor) centric, it has a higher likelihood of long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get in your constituents’ shoes and figure out what will surprise and delight them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/be-unpredictable-and-be-loved&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/05/09/be-unpredictable-and-be-loved.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/05/09/be-unpredictable-and-be-loved.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Custom vs. Comercial WordPress Themes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress themes control more than just how your site looks. They contain specific customizer values to help you control your site, bits of logic on how posts work, custom post type and meta definitions. In other words, your theme is what makes your website yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We build WordPress themes custom for each project. This isn’t necessarily the norm. Many shops start with a commercial theme or framework and build from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t start from scratch, that would be silly and wasteful. We take the 1,000 hour headstart &lt;a href=&quot;https://underscores.me/&quot;&gt;_s&lt;/a&gt; gets us. Underscores ( _s, get it ) is built by the team that makes WordPress and has all the basic components of a great theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cheescake-factory-vs-hisa-franco&quot;&gt;The Cheescake Factory vs. Hisa Franco&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you will indulge an extended culinary analogy, commercial themes are to T&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecheesecakefactory.com/&quot;&gt;he Cheescake Factory&lt;/a&gt; as custom themes are to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hisafranko.com/en/&quot;&gt;Hiša Franco&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not read in restaurant snobbery here. You can have a great meal at either restaurant. And functionally you will leave with a full belly. They are both dining experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiša Franco is a small restaurant in Slovenia. It was featured on the Netflix series &lt;em&gt;Chef’s Table&lt;/em&gt;. Also my wife and I ate and stayed there on our honeymoon. It was a great meal. I haven’t eaten at The Cheescake Factory, but people love the place. To the tune of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketwatch.com/investing/stock/cake/financials&quot;&gt;$2.28 billion&lt;/a&gt; in revenue in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cheescake Factory has more than 250 items on its menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hub/501409/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202018-05-04%20at%204.04.17%20PM.png?t=1540416452600&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202018-05-04%20at%204.04.17%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-05-04 at 4.04.17 PM&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in just four menu items we go from Shanghai to Louisiana with a stop in Italy and Evelyn’s house. The menu has something for everyone all the time. There isn’t a single cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to know what you are hungry for when you walk in, because they have everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how many ingredients need to be stocked in the kitchen at The Cheescake Factory. Think about training cooks to be able to make all these different dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial themes have something for everyone. They often have multiple header and footer options, a few potential blog layouts, and one one or two homepage designs. The mix and match plugins to provide features. They load multiple JavaScript libraries to enable all the possible functionality, even if you aren’t using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiša Franco has two menu items. Everyone at the table has to make the same choice. It’s a tasting menu so you either choose eight or eleven courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an allergy or dislike an item, they may be able to accommodate you, but they may not. The menu changes constantly based on what’s available. You can count on a few ingredients from the region, but good luck getting your favorite dish from last visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t go to Hiša Franco to eat a specific dish. You go because you trust the chef to give you the best food from that region for that season. It’s a unique experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom themes do limit your choices, but they are designed for your particular needs. They focus on performance, giving you only the components you need. They enable a very specific vision of your site to be realized with a bespoke back-end interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weapon-of-choice&quot;&gt;Weapon of Choice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a “right” answer here. There are choices and implications. Here are some reasons to choose each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commercial-theme&quot;&gt;Commercial Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You want the ability to change site layout often (monthly)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You aren’t exactly sure what your content will look like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need to launch your website in the next two weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-theme&quot;&gt;Custom Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You want specific functionality or content types beyond pages and posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website speed is of the highest importance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You plan to keep overall site layout consistent over time (two years or more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some important implications to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commercial-theme-1&quot;&gt;Commercial Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page speed is a ranking factor for Google search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your conversion rate drops seven percent per second of page load time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will need to manage a dozen or more plugin updates that can cause conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-theme-1&quot;&gt;Custom Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development will take at least a few weeks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to the overall layout may require developer time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You need a clear picture of your site content before development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-take&quot;&gt;Our Take&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We prefer the custom theme. Our website design process focuses on what makes your organization unique. We want that to continue into the development of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial themes are square and round pegs. But we find that most organizations aren’t square or circular holes. They are twisty and have their own shape that requires a custom solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think commercial themes have a place and we have used them on a project or two where it made sense. But the performance hit is just too big. When we can deliver the same content nearly twice as fast it’s worth the additional time and money to develop a custom theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We certainly don’t think everyone will agree, but that’s what our decade of experience has taught us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.abravenew.com/custom-vs.-comercial-wordpress-themes&quot;&gt;A Brave New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/05/04/custom-vs.-comercial-wordpress-themes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shoeinthedoor.com/2018/05/04/custom-vs.-comercial-wordpress-themes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
